NASA的深空探索系统早已在地球上开始了它的旅程
NASA’s new deep space exploration system has begun its journey right here on Earth,
它来自美国全部50个州，外加几个欧洲国家
in all 50 states and several European countries.
太空发射系统(SLS)的零件们
The pieces of the Space Launch System rocket
即将组装完成，在EM1任务中送猎户座到达人类从未到过的深空
that will send Orion farther than humans have ever been before during Exploration Mission One are nearing completion.
这些零件最终会被送到肯尼迪航天中心
All these parts will ultimately be brought together at Kennedy Space Center,
猎户座早已在那为任务做准备了
where Orion is currently being prepared for the mission,
最终总装成为一次发射就能送人类与货物去月球的超大火箭
to make one enormous rocket powerful enough to take astronauts and cargo to the Moon in a single launch,
或者送探测器前往深空，去探寻更多惊人的发现
or send robotic probes deep into the solar system to make amazing discoveries.
设计、测试、制造一枚能送宇航员重返月球的火箭
When you’re designing, testing and building the rocket that will take astronauts back to the Moon,
真的有很多细节要一步一步来
there really are a lot of small steps to get from here to there.
但这些小细节一点点造就了火箭的各种大零件
But those small steps add up to some really big rocket pieces.
从哪说起呢？
So where are we?
先说顶部，低温推进级会送猎户座进入最终的奔月轨道
Near the top of the rocket, the interim cryogenic propulsion stage will give Orion a push toward the Moon.
但它的使命还未完成
But its job isn’t done there.
除了猎户座，它还会释放13个立方星——鞋盒大的小型科学探测器
It will separate from Orion and 13 CubeSats – little spacecraft and science missions about the size of a shoebox
它们将从猎户座适配器中分离出来
– will be released into deep space from the Orion Stage Adapter.
这些立方星每个都有各自的任务
These little hitchhikers will each have their own mission.
有些会跟着去月球，有一个研究太空环境，有一个会去和陨石交会
Some will be going to the Moon, one will study space weather and one’s going to rendezvous an asteroid!
火箭的这些部分已经造好，准备就绪了
These parts of the rocket are finished and ready to go.
还有一个适配器会保护低温推进级的一部分
There’s another adapter that Partially covers the interim cryogenic propulsion stage
作为芯级与上面级的连接：发射载具分级适配器
and connects the core stage to the upper part of the rocket: the Launch Vehicle Stage Adapter.
工人们在给适配器做最后的处理
Workers are putting the finishing touches on this adapter.
接下来是芯级，火箭的脊梁骨
Next we come to the core stage, the backbone of the rocket.
新奥尔良米丘德装配厂的工程师已经造好芯级的五个部分
Engineers at Michoud Assembly Facility near New Orleans have built the five big components of the stage,
其中包括巨大的燃料罐
including the enormous fuel tanks.
他们现在在安装内部的计算机、线缆等一切芯级需要的零件设备
Now they’re outfitting the insides with computers, electrical cables and everything else the core stage will need.
然后五个部分将组装到一起
And then they’ll join the pieces together.
芯级底部是一台猛犸(×)四台RS-25发动机
At the bottom of the core stage are the four RS-25 engines
燃料来自芯级的液氢和液氧
that use liquid hydrogen and liquid oxygen stored in the core stage tanks.
这些发动机也整装待发
Those engines are ready now.
它们装有的最新的发动机早已饥渴难耐了
They‘ve got the latest computers installed and they’re go.
芯级两边的是两枚固推
Attached to the side of the core stage are two solid rocket boosters.
它们在起飞时提供绝大多数的推力，帮助SLS进入太空
They provide most of the thrust, or the big push, to get SLS to space.
固推中间塞燃料的部分就是它的发动机了
The central section of the boosters, where the propellant is stored, are the motors.
这部分也已经造好
They’re also complete.
顶部和底部——火箭术语叫"forward和aft部分"——也在做了
The top and bottom – or forward and aft, in rocketspeak -- parts of the boosters are still being readied for flight;
绝对不会咕咕咕的
they’ll soon be done too.
所以总结一哈，低温推进级：就绪
So, interim cryogenic propulsion stage: GO
猎户座适配器：就绪
Orion Stage Adapter: GO
发射载具分级适配器：就绪
Launch Vehicle Stage Adapter: READY
四台RS-25发动机：就绪
Four RS-25 engines: They’re a GO
固推发动机：就绪
Solid rocket motors: GO
固推前部和后部结构：在做了
Forward and aft booster structures: They’ll soon be done too.
芯级主体结构也已完成，内部也将完成组装
The core stage major structures are GO and the interiors are moving toward final assembly.
下次，我们将仔细看看这些是怎么组装到一起的
Next time, we’ll take a closer look at putting it all together,
因为条条大路通KSC
because all roads lead to Kennedy Space Center,
那将是EM1开始的地方
where Exploration Mission One will all come together.
字幕翻译给虫
就酱，我是Stephen Granade，记住去月球去火星真的没那么容易
Until then, I’m Stephen Granade, reminding you that there are No Small Steps to get to the Moon and Mars.